# César Rubén Pérez Valdés

Mobile: +52 55 3460 0793.

E-mail: perezvaldesruben@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>here</u>. Portfolio: <u>here</u>.

#### About Me.

IT professional and data analyst. As data analyst, I've solid experience in coding languages such as **Python** and **R**, non-procedural languages such as **SQL** and **HTML**, additional tools like **spreadsheet software** (such as **Excel** and **google sheets**) and BI tools such as **Microsoft Power BI** among others. As an IT professional, I've got the opportunity to work with operative systems such as **Windows** and **Linux**. During the last 6 years, I've been collaborating with international teams, experience that has helped me to develop my skills to adapt to environments that are challenging and constantly changing.

## **Work Experience.**

- Integon Service Co.
- Time lapse: May, 2022 to Present.
- Position: Data Analyst.
- About the role: Design, implement and test ETL pipelines, automate report creation and distribution, reconciliation between data sources.
- Quadient (GMC Software).
- Time lapse: May, 2019 to February,
- Position: **Software Support Analyst**.
- About the role: **Resolve** in a timely manner system issues affecting customers **CCM solutions**, these problems were mostly related to: databases, networks, algorithms, etc.

## Parallel Projects (half time - temporary).

- Academia Europea.
- Time lapse: June, 2023 to September, 2023.
- Position: **Teacher**.
- About the role: IT teacher for the Python and SQL classes

- Coderhouse.
- Time lapse:: October, 2022 to present.
- Position: **Tutor**.
- About the role: Helping Coderhouse students to develop new skills by providing feedback and guidance on their projects.

#### **Education.**

- Bachelor degree in Psychology (2010 2014), Universidad de Ecatepec.
- IT Technician (2005 2008), Colegio de Estudios Científicos y Tecnológicos del Estado de México (CECyTEM) Plantel Ecatepec 1.

### **E-Learning and Certifications.**

- Information Technology Specialist Python.
- Information Technology Specialist Databases.
- Google Data Analytics Program.
- Data Science Fundamentals with Python and SQL.
- Google IT Automation with Python.
- Python For Everybody.
- Web Design For Everybody.